# SOFÍA IGNACIA ZAMBRANO MERICQ

Santiago, Chile +569 9020 5020

sofi.zambrano@gmail.com
https://sofizambrano.github.io/

### SUMMARY

Web and mobile developer specialized in front-end development. I consider myself very passionate for GUI design and I look forward to keep learning skills to improve in it. I love practicing advanced choreographic steps, teaching math, solving Sudoku puzzles, taking pictures and travelling. I am a very responsible, critical thinker and multi-tasker person, good at handicrafts and artistic work.

## **EXPERIENCE**

constraints.

educarchile: iOS mobile application developer	Mar 2017 – Jul 2017
I experienced what is like to work with a real client and having intensive team	
work. I learned how to build a native mobile application for iOS using Swift. My	
work focused on requirement analysis, view designs and dealing with	

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile: Software Engineering teaching assistant	Aug 2016 – Dec 2016
Experience as a product owner of other students, taught good practices for coding in Ruby on Rails.	

Software Engineering Class Project: Ruby on Rails web application developer	Mar 2016 – Jul 2016
I learned how to build a web application using Ruby on Rails framework. The	
application purpose was to offer an online free book llibrary, where users could	
search, classify with taas, read, convert and share books.	

Databases Class Project: PHP web application developer	Mar 2016 – Jul 2016
I learned PHP interactions with a PostgreSQL database for developing a	
simple web social network integrated with a site for searching movies.	

<b>Pontifical Catholic University of Chile:</b> Introduction to Programming teaching assistant	Aug 2016 – Dec 2016 Aug 2014 – Dec 2014
I taught Python language in laboratory sessions for first and second year	

students motivating and guiding them to solve programming challenges.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming languages: Python, Ruby, Swift, PHP, HTML, CSS SQL database queries, deployment with Heroku platform and version control with GitHub repositories.

Bilingual: Spanish native speaker and English fluent speaker (ETS TOEIC Exam 905/990 points; IELTS Academic Exam 7.0 overall band score)
Instruments: piano and flute

# **EDUCATION**

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile, Santiago, Chile	Mar 2012 – Jul 2018
Software Engineering	
Episcopal High School of Jacksonville, Jacksonville, FL, USA	Nov 2009 – Feb 2010
Dunalastair School, Santiago, Chile	Jul 1998 – Dec 2011
Glenbrook Cooperative Nursery Preschool, Bethesda, MD, USA	Mar 1995 – Jul 1998